Guide to the Stanford Research Institute Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Research Institute records
1947-1966
SC0801
Stanford Research Institute.
1.5 Linear feet
Collection consists primarily of minutes of the Board of Directors and the Executive Committee, with some reports, financial statements, correspondence, memoranda, articles and brochures. Topics include research projects, financing, board membership, equipment needs, facility growth, and other administrative issues.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Research Institute was organized in 1946 as an applied research center for industry and government. In 1970 it became independent from Stanford University and in 1977 changed its name to SRI International.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists primarily of minutes of the Board of Directors and the Executive Committee, with some reports, financial statements, correspondence, memoranda, articles and brochures. Topics include research projects, financing, board membership, equipment needs, facility growth, and other administrative issues.
Access Terms
SRI International; Stanford Research Institute.; Academic-industrial collaboration --United States.; Research institutes.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Governors – 1947 – 49 [1 of 2]: Election of Board Members; Finances (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Governors – 1947 – 49 [2 of 2]: Finances (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors – 1949 – 50 [1 of 2]: Current Projects; Budget (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors – 1949 – 50 [2 of 2]: Project Updates; Financial Audit; Resignation of Dr. Eurich (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Governors – 1950 – 51 [1 of 2]: Research Report; Financial Report (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Governors – 1950 – 51 [2 of 2]: Financial Report; Resolution to Limit Liability (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Governors – 1951 – 52 [1 of 2]: Financial Report; RFC Loan; Executive Committee Report (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Governors – 1951 – 52 [2 of 2]: Financial Operations; Budget; Elections; Contracts (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors – 1952 – 53 [1 of 2]: Financial Statements; Contracts; Retirement Plans (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors – 1952 – 53 [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors – 1954 [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors – 1954 [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors – 1955-56 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Executive Committees of the Board of Directors (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Minutes and Reports – 1960-61 [1 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Minutes and Reports – 1960-61 [2 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Minutes and Reports – 1960-61 [3 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Minutes and Reports – 1960-61 [4 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Minutes and Reports – 1961-62 [1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Minutes and Reports – 1961-62 [2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors Minutes [1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors Minutes [2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors Minutes – 1965-66 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Research Institute – Board of Directors Minutes – 1963-65 (Box 3, Folder 6)
General note
These materials were originally sent to the university president's office.